<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="http://blogs.office.com/utility/FeedStylesheets/rss.xsl" media="screen"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"><channel><title>SharePoint Blog</title><link>http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/default.aspx</link><description /><dc:language>en-US</dc:language><generator>Telligent Community 1.5.134.15456 (Build: 5.5.134.15456)</generator><item><title>Paris airport management uses SharePoint 2013 search tools to enhance knowledge sharing</title><link>http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/2013/03/11/paris-airport-management-uses-sharepoint-2013-search-tools-to-enhance-knowledge-sharing.aspx</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">53587256-c606-4c9b-bad4-97c86b12ce62:36171</guid><dc:creator>SharePoint Team</dc:creator><slash:comments>0</slash:comments><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/rsscomments.aspx?WeblogPostID=36171</wfw:commentRss><comments>http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/2013/03/11/paris-airport-management-uses-sharepoint-2013-search-tools-to-enhance-knowledge-sharing.aspx#comments</comments><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Today's post is the first in a series spotlighting success stories from SharePoint 2013 early adopters.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;img src="http://blogs.office.com/resized-image.ashx/__size/205x0/__key/CommunityServer-Blogs-Components-WeblogFiles/00-00-00-00-64/7838.adp.png" border="0" style="float: left;" /&gt;Employees get fast and intuitive access to two terabytes of data &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A&amp;eacute;roports de Paris, which owns and manages the 13 civil airports and airfields in the &amp;Icirc;le-de-France (Paris) area, wanted to make it easier for employees to search efficiently, share knowledge, and deliver faster service to airport passengers, employees, and partners. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The organization had been using Microsoft SharePoint Server 2010 to run its enterprise content management system. The system contains two terabytes of data, two million objects, 1,500 sites, and 69 content databases. To help employees discover information faster, A&amp;eacute;roports de Paris decided to upgrade to SharePoint 2013. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We wanted to create a better sense of community and help employees find colleagues who might have the answers to their questions," says Cedric Krouri, IT Project Manager at A&amp;eacute;roports de Paris. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A&amp;eacute;roports de Paris worked with Microsoft Services Consulting and Exakis, a member of the Microsoft Partner Network, to implement Microsoft SharePoint 2013. The migration preparation process took two weeks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The organization is eager to take advantage of advanced SharePoint 2013 search features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search results are organized according to the type of documents (such as Microsoft PowerPoint presentations) that the employee uses most often and the results that other employees have found most useful. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When an employee hovers over an individual's name in a search result, he or she can see a contact card that provides information on what that colleague has worked on regarding the search topic. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All information is searchable as soon as it is posted. Search results show document previews, and direct employees to the specific places within a document where the search term occurs. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SharePoint 2013 can generate comprehensive search results even when terms or names are misspelled. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A&amp;eacute;roports de Paris employees can use SharePoint 2013 to help find higher-quality information, and the solution's social computing features will help employees verify quality by letting them quickly contact the author or a subject matter expert. Says Pierre Siffrin, Technical Lead for SharePoint at A&amp;eacute;roports de Paris, "By using the enhanced search and social capabilities in SharePoint 2013, employees will be able to locate the best documents faster." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more on how Paris Airport Management uses SharePoint 2013 to enhance knowledge sharing, please see the complete &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.microsoft.com/casestudies/Case_Study_Detail.aspx?CaseStudyID=710000001619"&gt;case study&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://blogs.office.com/aggbug.aspx?PostID=36171" width="1" height="1"&gt;</description><category domain="http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/tags/SharePoint+2013/default.aspx">SharePoint 2013</category><category domain="http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/tags/Customer+Stories/default.aspx">Customer Stories</category></item><item><title>Enhanced Video Experience in SharePoint 2013</title><link>http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/2013/03/08/enhanced-video-experience-in-sharepoint-2013.aspx</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">53587256-c606-4c9b-bad4-97c86b12ce62:36142</guid><dc:creator>SharePoint Team</dc:creator><slash:comments>1</slash:comments><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/rsscomments.aspx?WeblogPostID=36142</wfw:commentRss><comments>http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/2013/03/08/enhanced-video-experience-in-sharepoint-2013.aspx#comments</comments><description>&lt;p&gt;A picture is worth a thousand words, but did you know that a video is worth a thousand pictures? Videos are revolutionizing the way teams and organizations communicate with each other and are increasingly being used to facilitate knowledge-sharing and training within organizations. Intranet video portals for the enterprise are gaining popularity because they are effective for sharing information across the entire organization. SharePoint 2013 does a great job supporting video communications-from sharing a video across a team site to building a knowledge management/video portal for the enterprise. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video experience&amp;nbsp;in SharePoint 2013 is enhanced greatly-the videos are easier to upload, the UI is clean and simple,&amp;nbsp;videos are easy to search,&amp;nbsp;and more! Let's walk through it...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How are videos organized?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand how videos in SharePoint 2013 work, it is important to understand how videos are organized. Videos are organized in a manner similar to document sets, which is a group of related documents that can be created in a single step and managed as one entity. To learn more about document sets, see &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://office.microsoft.com/en-us/sharepoint-server-help/introduction-to-document-sets-HA101782466.aspx"&gt;Introduction to document sets&lt;/a&gt;. SharePoint creates a stub (think of it as a folder) to hold a video and all the related contents, such as user-defined properties, thumbnails, video renditions, and other documents related to the video.&amp;nbsp;When you upload a video file, SharePoint automatically creates this stub for that video. You can imagine the video set to be the encapsulation of everything related to that video. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next few sections, we'll talk about how videos can be uploaded, watched, and searched in SharePoint 2013. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The new video player page&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SharePoint 2013 offers a video player page for each video, which surfaces the video with its metadata and all the properties the user fills in. These&amp;nbsp;include name, description, owner, the people in video, and keywords-to name a few. Videos can be played from the video player page. The way SharePoint organizes the videos, together with the default video player page, greatly simplifies the process of building a video portal for your organization. (And soon, watch out for the white paper on how to build a social media sharing site on SharePoint 2013 for your enterprise.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users can also enable a download link and embed code in the video player page. So, now viewers can download a video from your site, and/or embed this video in a different site. Another cool feature in the video player page is the ability to add related items. Imagine you upload a video of a presentation, but you also want to add the PowerPoint deck used in that presentation for your viewers. In SharePoint 2013, it's right alongside! Simply drag and drop the relevant files that you feel the viewers of this video should see. Everything&amp;nbsp;is in a&lt;i&gt;&amp;nbsp;single&lt;/i&gt; page!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;img src="http://blogs.office.com/resized-image.ashx/__size/550x0/__key/CommunityServer-Blogs-Components-WeblogFiles/00-00-00-00-64/0272.image_2D00_1a.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Figure 1. The video player page&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a glimpse of the video edit form where users can add&amp;nbsp;relevant metadata.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;img src="http://blogs.office.com/resized-image.ashx/__size/550x0/__key/CommunityServer-Blogs-Components-WeblogFiles/00-00-00-00-64/3644.image_2D00_2b.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Figure 2. The video edit form&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Media players in SharePoint 2013&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SharePoint 2013 has a built-in HTML5 media player that is used to play all video files that are compatible with the HTML5 &lt;b&gt;&amp;lt;video&amp;gt;&lt;/b&gt; implementation for the current browser. This means you can now play videos on mobile devices such as iOS that don't support Silverlight. If the format is not playable by the HTML5 player, then we use Silverlight. The video is auto-played&amp;nbsp;when the user opens the video player page.&amp;nbsp;The player streams video content using the BLOB cache, progressive streaming, and bit-rate throttling in the same manner as the SharePoint 2010 media player. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the list of media formats supported by HTML5 in the Wikipedia article &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTML5_video#Supported_video_formats"&gt;HTML5 video&lt;/a&gt;, and the list of media formats supported by Silverlight in the article &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/cc189080(VS.95).aspx"&gt;Supported media formats, protocols, and log fields&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both media players support exposing an embed code and switching renditions on-the-fly. The video renditions feature lets you upload multiple renditions of a video-whether they are different codecs/formats or different bitrates. You can switch seamlessly on-the-fly just by choosing the desired rendition from the media player. By default, the video with the lowest bitrate is chosen, to conserve bandwidth. You can always change the default rendition from the Manage Renditions page. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a screenshot of the HTML5 player on Internet Explorer 10. You can see the full screen, embed code, and switch renditions icons on the video player. And, Yes! We are touch-friendly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;img src="http://blogs.office.com/resized-image.ashx/__size/550x0/__key/CommunityServer-Blogs-Components-WeblogFiles/00-00-00-00-64/6404.image_2D00_3.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Figure 3. The HTML5 media player&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Uploading a video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Videos can be uploaded to any library, but you can get the most out of SharePoint if you upload videos to a library that has the video content type enabled. For example, the Asset Library, which is customized for storing digital assets. You can enable the video content type in other libraries by adding video from the existing site content types in the library settings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uploading a video is as simple as dragging the files into the drop target. We all know the web has evolved tremendously over the years. Many users think of drag and drop when they want to upload a file, and I'm excited that SharePoint fulfils that expectation. Drag and drop really simplifies life when it comes to uploading hundreds of files to a library. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drag and drop can be used when your file resides in your computer or a file share, but what if you want to surface your videos from an external site (like YouTube) on SharePoint? For this scenario, we have a second way to upload videos through the new document option on the ribbon. On the &lt;b&gt;Files&lt;/b&gt; tab on the ribbon, in the new group, choosing a video from the new document drop-down menu gives you three options:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Upload video from my computer:&lt;/b&gt; Use this option to upload videos from your computer using Windows Explorer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul type="disc"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Provide a link to a video:&lt;/b&gt; Use this option to provide a link to a video file that resides in another site (such as videos from other SharePoint sites or file shares). It is important to note that your URL should point to a video stream file and not to a video player URL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Provide code to embed a video from the web:&lt;/b&gt; Use this option to paste the embed code for your video from anywhere on the web (for example, YouTube). So, if your organization has a channel on YouTube with a collection of videos, you can now keep track and view those videos on your internal SharePoint site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Options two and three enable users to create SharePoint videos from a variety of sources, even though the video file is not physically stored in SharePoint. SharePoint knows how to treat each of these files and ensures you get the relevant features regardless of the way you create them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Video thumbnailing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We provide two types of thumbnailing: server-generated and user-selected. In server-generated thumbnailing, all that you have to do is upload your videos to a library with the video content type enabled, and SharePoint automatically generates thumbnails for your videos without you having to do anything else. Note that thumbnails are available only for formats for which the Windows Media Foundation on the server can generate thumbnails, meaning additional formats can be supported by additional codecs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second option is user-selected thumbnailing. You can use our client-side thumbnail generator to set those perfect moments as thumbnails for your videos, in case the server-generated thumbnail is not the one you want to use. The thumbnail generator can be accessed from the video edit form. When you choose the change thumbnail link, you get an option to capture thumbnail from video, use a picture from my computer, or use a picture from a web address. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a look at the screenshot below, where I captured a different thumbnail for my video using the camera icon, and the thumbnail is immediately reflected in the thumbnail previewer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;img src="http://blogs.office.com/resized-image.ashx/__size/550x0/__key/CommunityServer-Blogs-Components-WeblogFiles/00-00-00-00-64/0028.image_2D00_4b.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Figure 4. Video thumbnailing&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tagging, ratings, and view count in videos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other cool features in the video space include video tagging, rating, and view counts. All these features take you a step closer in personalizing your video experience. You can now tag people in videos to help viewers&amp;nbsp;know the people in that video. Enabling ratings from the library settings lets&amp;nbsp;viewers rate your videos.&amp;nbsp;This is especially useful when you want to have a way for your users to view the most rated or most popular videos in your portal. SharePoint also has a powerful analytics database that provides view counts on the video player page after&amp;nbsp;search finishes crawling your video. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Videos in search-find videos easier and faster&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the enhancements we've discussed wouldn't be complete without giving your users a better way to &lt;i&gt;find&lt;/i&gt; the videos they care about the most. Search in SharePoint 2013 is full of enhancements and video is no exception. To start, let us introduce you to how we in the engineering team think of videos and search. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Everything vertical-your videos stand out from the crowd&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the top of the search results page, you'll notice category headings underneath the search bar. We call these &lt;i&gt;verticals&lt;/i&gt;. The one you'll experience most often is the Everything vertical, where we display search results from all kinds of content types. Documents, pages, images, videos, and so on., all displayed on the same page. In the result list, on the Everything search result page (see Figure 5), you'll see that videos stand out from pages and other content (kind of like documents do) with a thumbnail of the video on the right side of the result list. If you know it's a video you're searching for, the thumbnail in the search result gives you an easy visual cue that can help you identify what is and isn't a video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video intent group-understanding your video searches&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding videos can be a daunting task when you have hundreds of thousands, if not millions, of pieces to sort through. Not only did we ensure that your search results are relevant to your search query, but we went a step further. We actually analyze your search terms and determine whether we think you were searching for video content. When this happens, you'll see a grouping of the most-relevant videos matching your search query appear at the top of your search result page, allowing you to zero in on the video you wanted to find faster than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hover cards and callouts-a window to your videos&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hover over any search result in the organic result list and you'll see what we named a hover card. This card is a peek into the item you're hovering over, and its content is dependent on the type of result you're looking at. For videos in particular, the hover card shows you the video's name, length, the people present in the video, who uploaded it, and so on. Most importantly though, it features an actual video player so you can watch or preview the video right then and there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;img src="http://blogs.office.com/resized-image.ashx/__size/550x0/__key/CommunityServer-Blogs-Components-WeblogFiles/00-00-00-00-64/8741.image_2D00_5_2D00_final.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Figure 5. Videos in the Everything vertical&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;img src="http://blogs.office.com/resized-image.ashx/__size/550x0/__key/CommunityServer-Blogs-Components-WeblogFiles/00-00-00-00-64/2474.image_2D00_6_2D00_final.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Figure 6. Video-specific result blocks&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Videos vertical-all videos, all the time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember the verticals I mentioned a few paragraphs up? The places where search results are grouped by their type? Video is no exception, and this is where you can go if you want to filter your results immediately to just videos. But, that's just the beginning. We know that video search is an area that's incredibly important, and we're really proud of the experience we've built. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of the Videos vertical as your video search command center. We designed this experience with the intent of enabling you to do as much on this specific page as possible. Here you can see many video search results and their thumbnails. Watching a video is a time-intensive task, and your time is valuable, so we didn't want to make figuring out what video to watch a time-intensive task as well. With that in mind, we also added information below each result-view counts and duration-to help you decide which video is the one you want. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember the hover card from the Everything results vertical? We wanted to give you all the great information and inline playing experience from that card here as well, but in a way that worked well with the video-specific thumbnail layout. Now, when you choose a thumbnail in the Videos vertical, we pull up the &lt;i&gt;callout&lt;/i&gt; (that is, the on-click version of the hover card) with all of the great video information you expect. At the top of the callout, as with the hover card, is a built-in video player. All of these great features put together create a one-stop shop for finding your videos and watching them, without having to navigate between multiple pages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;img src="http://blogs.office.com/resized-image.ashx/__size/550x0/__key/CommunityServer-Blogs-Components-WeblogFiles/00-00-00-00-64/6318.image_2D00_7_2D00_final.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Figure 7. Video search results formatted for videos&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In&amp;nbsp;SharePoint 2013, videos are treated as a content type as opposed to just a file, which provides a more complete experience for creating, uploading, finding, sharing, and viewing videos. Let us know in the comments about your favorite features in SharePoint 2013. Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Vidya Srinivasan and David Cohen are Program Managers on the SharePoint Enterprise Content Management team, and are responsible for the video experience in SharePoint 2013.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://blogs.office.com/aggbug.aspx?PostID=36142" width="1" height="1"&gt;</description><category domain="http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/tags/SharePoint+2013/default.aspx">SharePoint 2013</category><category domain="http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/tags/video/default.aspx">video</category><category domain="http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/tags/enterprise+content+management/default.aspx">enterprise content management</category><category domain="http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/tags/ECM/default.aspx">ECM</category></item><item><title>Out and about: New SharePoint mobile offerings</title><link>http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/2013/03/06/out-and-about-new-sharepoint-mobile-offerings.aspx</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 18:30:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">53587256-c606-4c9b-bad4-97c86b12ce62:36060</guid><dc:creator>SharePoint Team</dc:creator><slash:comments>13</slash:comments><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/rsscomments.aspx?WeblogPostID=36060</wfw:commentRss><comments>http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/2013/03/06/out-and-about-new-sharepoint-mobile-offerings.aspx#comments</comments><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work is no longer 9-5, nor confined to a single location. People are out and about more than ever and need to be able to access their documents and data whenever and wherever they are. As we shared at &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/news/Press/2012/Nov12/11-12SPCPR.aspx"&gt;SharePoint Conference 2012&lt;/a&gt; in November, we've been working hard on new SharePoint mobile apps so you can access your information from a variety of devices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm&amp;nbsp;excited to share an update on the progress we've made--from the new native apps and how SharePoint document access appears in the native Windows Phone Office Hub to investments in cross-device access across multiple browsers and a new backend feature called Device Channels. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Two&amp;nbsp;new apps available across multiple devices&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're introducing two new&amp;nbsp;apps across multiple devices: the SharePoint Newsfeed app and the SkyDrive Pro app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The SharePoint Newsfeed app. &lt;/b&gt;The SharePoint Newsfeed app--available now for Windows Phone and iOS mobile devices--is the best way to stay connected and be productive while on the go. You can use the SharePoint Newsfeed app to interact with your organization's SharePoint social network, letting you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create new status posts, use #hashtags, @mention direct to a colleague&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add comments to ongoing discussions, read and "like" your colleagues' posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upload pictures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://aka.ms/sharepointmobile"&gt;And more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can try the new app now, installed directly on your device. The apps will work against a Microsoft Office 365 SharePoint Online account or a properly configured on-premises SharePoint Server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SharePoint Newsfeed for Windows Phone: &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://aka.ms/SPWP"&gt;http://aka.ms/SPWP&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SharePoint Newsfeed for iOS: &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://aka.ms/SPiOS"&gt;http://aka.ms/SPiOS&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SharePoint Newsfeed for Windows 8 modern app: (coming in Summer of 2013)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://blogs.office.com/resized-image.ashx/__size/550x0/__key/CommunityServer-Blogs-Components-WeblogFiles/00-00-00-00-64/3463.sharepoint-app-on-windows.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The new SharePoint Newsfeed app on a Windows Phone. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://blogs.office.com/resized-image.ashx/__size/550x0/__key/CommunityServer-Blogs-Components-WeblogFiles/00-00-00-00-64/5482.sharepoint-app-for-ios.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The new SharePoint Newsfeed app for iOS - left image shows app displayed on an iPad, right image shows app displayed on an iPhone.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The SkyDrive Pro app. &lt;/b&gt;As you may know, SkyDrive Pro is cloud storage that organizations provision for employees as part of their SharePoint 2013 on-premises and/or Office 365 SharePoint Online deployments.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This personal file storage service is for business use, and users can store, access and synchronize their files using the SkyDrive Pro client software.&amp;nbsp; Users are not limited to synchronizing their personal docs--they can sync any document library to which they have permission (for document libraries where sync is turned on).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we shared at SharePoint Conference, we're working on native SkyDrive Pro apps for Windows 8 and iOS, both will be coming in summer of 2013. There, too, is a Windows desktop client that ships with Office 2013--and soon this "folder sync" technology will ship as a free, standalone installable client. In addition, the capabilities already come natively in Windows Phone (more on that below in the Office Hub section of this post).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use the SkyDrive Pro app for Windows 8 and iOS to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;View documents in your SkyDrive Pro folder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select specific content to take offline when you travel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upload new content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create new folders and organize&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://sharepoint.microsoft.com/blog/Pages/BlogPost.aspx?pID=1033"&gt;Learn more about SkyDrive Pro.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://blogs.office.com/resized-image.ashx/__size/550x0/__key/CommunityServer-Blogs-Components-WeblogFiles/00-00-00-00-64/4426.image_2D00_6.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;SkyDrive Pro for Windows 8 modern app--early design concept screenshots, not final renditions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Windows Phone Office Hub&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here on the SharePoint team, we've been collaborating with the Windows Phone team for some time now. As a result, Windows Phone 8 comes with an updated Office Hub, in which SharePoint provides the embedded SkyDrive Pro technology so you can have access to your documents wherever you are. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use the Windows Phone Office Hub to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find documents, open them and make last-minute changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quickly find and open documents you've recently used &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start new documents&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://blogs.office.com/resized-image.ashx/__size/465x0/__key/CommunityServer-Blogs-Components-WeblogFiles/00-00-00-00-64/7573.image_2D00_3.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Windows Phone 8 Office Hub. &lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp; In the graphic above under 'places', 'Mark Kashman'&amp;nbsp;represents a SharePoint Online hosted SkyDrive Pro folder.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cross-device access across multiple browsers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its core, SharePoint is all about dynamic sites and the various business solutions you can easily configure through out-of-the-box templates. The new SharePoint user interface is a refreshing, clean experience with easy drag and drop, quicker page loads and a focus on true accessibility using WCAG guidelines to make SharePoint perceivable, operable, understandable and robust. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://blogs.office.com/b/officewebapps/archive/2012/08/20/bringing-touch-editing-to-office-web-apps-on-windows-8-and-ios-tablets.aspx"&gt;Touch&lt;/a&gt; was a key area of investment across all of the products in the new Office, and SharePoint is no exception. For SharePoint, we focused on building large touch targets as you filter and navigate and even work with documents. The Office Web Apps team also focused on making the browser-based Office experience accessible across devices, big and small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://blogs.office.com/resized-image.ashx/__size/550x0/__key/CommunityServer-Blogs-Components-WeblogFiles/00-00-00-00-64/6428.image_2D00_4.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SharePoint is now more touch friendly across all types of devices&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specific to the small screens found in today's smartphones, we built native mobile viewing experiences--turning your pages into HTML5 app-like solutions. In Mobile View mode, the design elements are stripped away so that the essence of distinct tasks are front and center--like working with a document, viewing the full timeline of a project and adding a new item to a list.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://blogs.office.com/resized-image.ashx/__size/550x0/__key/CommunityServer-Blogs-Components-WeblogFiles/00-00-00-00-64/5305.image_2D00_5.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SharePoint mobile browser activities (left to right): document libraries, timeline and creating a new task.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/fp161353.aspx"&gt;See the lists of supported mobile device browsers in SharePoint 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Device Channels&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In support of bring-your-own-devices (BYOD), SharePoint now enables unique, curated experiences via the new Device Channel feature. This is ideal for more complex SharePoint sites where you create a single site and author content for that site, but map the content to use different master pages and style sheets that are specific to a device or group of devices that you choose--rendering the best experience possible for the variety of large and small screens connecting to your company portal. SharePoint helps by auto-detecting the users' device and serving up your custom templates. The design work is typically done by a Web developer or designer. And uploading and enabling the various templates is an easy IT Pro task. Note, device channels are only available for publishing sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://office.microsoft.com/en-us/office365-sharepoint-online-enterprise-help/redir/XT103470729.aspx?CTT=5&amp;amp;origin=HA102895211"&gt;Learn more about Device Channels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SharePoint on the go&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life happens, and the latest SharePoint mobile investments make it easier for you to access the content you need wherever you are across a variety of devices. Try &lt;a href="http://office.microsoft.com/en-us/products/office-products-FX101825692.aspx?CTT=97"&gt;Office 365&lt;/a&gt; today and test out the mobile SharePoint capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;--Mark Kashman,&amp;nbsp;SharePoint Senior Product Manager&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://blogs.office.com/aggbug.aspx?PostID=36060" width="1" height="1"&gt;</description><category domain="http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/tags/SharePoint+2013/default.aspx">SharePoint 2013</category><category domain="http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/tags/SharePoint/default.aspx">SharePoint</category><category domain="http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/tags/apps/default.aspx">apps</category><category domain="http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/tags/web+apps/default.aspx">web apps</category></item><item><title>Options to Create Forms in SharePoint 2013</title><link>http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/2013/03/04/options-to-create-forms-in-sharepoint-2013.aspx</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">53587256-c606-4c9b-bad4-97c86b12ce62:36012</guid><dc:creator>SharePoint Team</dc:creator><slash:comments>6</slash:comments><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/rsscomments.aspx?WeblogPostID=36012</wfw:commentRss><comments>http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/2013/03/04/options-to-create-forms-in-sharepoint-2013.aspx#comments</comments><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Senior Product Marketing Manager Keenan Newton introduces multiple options available for forms creation with Office 2013 and SharePoint 2013.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forms are an intricate part of many organizations as they feed information into business processes that allow the organization to manage day-to-day processes.&amp;nbsp; Forms are used for internal processes such as hardware and software acquisition as well as externally for collecting information on a new potential customer. &lt;a&gt;For&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;almost a decade, we've delivered a best-in-class forms experience as part of Microsoft Office.&amp;nbsp; As with much in the technology world, customer needs in the forms space have evolved and, with the new Office and new SharePoint, we have enhanced the forms experience to meet these needs.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have a choice of tools for building forms with SharePoint, including InfoPath, Access, Excel, and Visual Studio. These tools can create custom forms within a SharePoint solution or an app for SharePoint. Below is an overview of the tool choices, including the benefits and common scenarios for each. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;InfoPath&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;InfoPath is our integrated forms solution for the foreseeable future. It's a great choice for business users who want to customize lists or who want advanced features such as offline editing or digital signatures. You also can use InfoPath 2013 to maintain existing InfoPath forms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Access &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Access 2013 now addresses scenarios in which a business user wants to rapidly create end-to-end web-based business solutions, including those that involve custom forms. Some examples of business solutions that are prime candidates for Access 2013 include apps for asset management, contact management, and inventory management. Business solutions created with Access 2013, packaged into apps, and deployed onto SharePoint can be used by anyone within an organization or shared externally via the SharePoint Store.&amp;nbsp; For new end-to-end business solutions that include forms, we recommend that you consider Access 2013 first, because of its end-to-end solution design focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Excel&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have included forms in Excel Web Apps for building simple forms such as surveys or simple data collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Visual Studio&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For application development, we recommend Visual Studio so you can use the capabilities provided in the new &lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/officeapps/archive/2012/07/17/introducing-the-new-office-cloud-app-model.aspx"&gt;cloud app model&lt;/a&gt; for Office and SharePoint, which embraces current web standards such as HTML5, enables web developers to build solutions with the developer tools and platforms they know best. For developers who require the unique capabilities of InfoPath, such as digital signatures, you can now use the full power of Visual Studio to extend InfoPath solutions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, our products provide a lot of flexibility for business users to create forms-based solutions. Deciding the right tool to use will of course be ultimately dependent on your specific needs, but I hope that this post will help give you some guidance on what to choose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://blogs.office.com/aggbug.aspx?PostID=36012" width="1" height="1"&gt;</description><category domain="http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/tags/SharePoint+2013/default.aspx">SharePoint 2013</category><category domain="http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/tags/SharePoint/default.aspx">SharePoint</category><category domain="http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/tags/Access/default.aspx">Access</category><category domain="http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/tags/Excel/default.aspx">Excel</category><category domain="http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/tags/InfoPath/default.aspx">InfoPath</category><category domain="http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/tags/developer/default.aspx">developer</category><category domain="http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/tags/Visual+Studio/default.aspx">Visual Studio</category></item><item><title>Create your online brand with a combination of SharePoint 2013 and the web technologies you already know </title><link>http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/2013/02/25/create-your-online-brand-with-sharepoint-2013-and-the-web-technologies-you-already-know.aspx</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">53587256-c606-4c9b-bad4-97c86b12ce62:35952</guid><dc:creator>SharePoint Team</dc:creator><slash:comments>7</slash:comments><wfw:commentRss xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/">http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/rsscomments.aspx?WeblogPostID=35952</wfw:commentRss><comments>http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/2013/02/25/create-your-online-brand-with-sharepoint-2013-and-the-web-technologies-you-already-know.aspx#comments</comments><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This post is an introduction to how you can easily use the Design Manager alongside the web design tools you're most comfortable with to define your company's online brand&amp;nbsp;using the&amp;nbsp;strong content-management capabilities system that is SharePoint 2013.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://blogs.office.com/resized-image.ashx/__size/550x0/__key/CommunityServer-Blogs-Components-WeblogFiles/00-00-00-00-64/5672.SUMMARY_5F00_SharePoint_5F00_300x166_5F00_V1.jpg" alt="Branding with SharePoint" title="Branding with SharePoint" style="border: 0px currentColor; margin-right: 12px;  float: left;" /&gt;With SharePoint 2013, you can brand your SharePoint publishing site&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;using the web technologies you know, the tools you like, and the devices you want, making it easier than ever before to get started as a SharePoint designer or developer. And for current SharePoint pros, don't worry. The work you've put in learning SharePoint thus far is still very applicable and your knowledge of the SharePoint Publishing Page model is still incredibly useful. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post provides an overview of how you can easily use the SharePoint 2013 Design Manager and Device Channels alongside the web design tools you're most comfortable with to define your company's online brand. While keeping the same page rendering infrastructure, we've made three major enhancements to how you brand a SharePoint Publishing site. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Use the web technologies you know&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SharePoint still maintains its master pages and page layouts in ASP.NET, but now you can&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;also design your master pages and page layouts in HTML, including using HTML snippets of SharePoint controls. In the background, SharePoint creates the corresponding ASP.NET file that it wants but that you get to ignore. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, you could use CSS and JavaScript to style your site, but now those are fully integrated into your SharePoint web development experience. We did a lot of work with HTML previewing so you can style the HTML directly rather than having to use the server to see it. And if you do preview on the server, you can do so in the context of any SharePoint page of your choice! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working in the web technologies you know doesn't&amp;nbsp;stop at the page layout level. The Content Query Web Part that required you to design in XSLT is still around, but the new Content Search Web Part is an important building block for creating search-driven experiences in SharePoint 2013.&amp;nbsp;Making sure that there was a great designer experience to go along with it was very important for us, so it is customizable with JavaScript, HTML, and CSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because we aren't assuming any SharePoint knowledge on your part, we have the Design Manager to help walk you through the branding of your publishing site. This Design Manager provides a wizard-like experience to give you SharePoint development guidance side-by-side with entry points for you to view and work with your design files. Each of the steps&amp;nbsp;also has its own documentation article on MSDN:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/jj822363.aspx"&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/jj733517.aspx"&gt;Manage Device Channels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/jj733519.aspx"&gt;Upload Design Files&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/jj822370.aspx"&gt;Edit Master Pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/jj945138.aspx"&gt;Edit Display Templates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/jj822368.aspx"&gt;Edit Page Layouts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/jj862339.aspx"&gt;Publish and Apply Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/jj862342.aspx"&gt;Create Design Package&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Customize SharePoint with the tools you like&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customizing the design of your site is more than converting HTML into ASP.NET. To help you be successful in creating your site, popular placeholders are ready and waiting for your content. When it comes to page layouts, we inserted all the page fields that are unique to the content type you choose--this way, creating your SharePoint design files turns into a matter of editing and tweaking rather than creating. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the Snippet Gallery, you have a good starting point for adding SharePoint functionality to your site. For those of you familiar with previous versions of SharePoint, think of this as the set of controls that you'd access from SharePoint Designer--but a bit more than that. The Snippet Gallery provides an HTML version (including, in many cases, a static preview to show you what you're working with while you edit your file in something like Dreamweaver split view) of a set of common components--&lt;i&gt;including all Web Parts from the Web Part gallery&lt;/i&gt;. For each snippet, you get to tweak its properties and simply copy it into your HTML master page or page layout, and in the background, SharePoint turns it into the ASP.NET control it requires. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://blogs.office.com/resized-image.ashx/__size/550x0/__key/CommunityServer-Blogs-Components-WeblogFiles/00-00-00-00-64/5265.SHAREPOINT-IMAGE-01.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 1.&lt;/strong&gt; At the top of the page of the Snippet Gallery is a ribbon of all the snippets. The body of the page has the snippet's description, properties and HTML code, plus a live preview. Every master page has the same snippet gallery, which is slightly different from that of page layouts--and the snippet gallery of a page layout depends on its content type (because the page fields change).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Experience SharePoint on any device &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are no longer simply accessing your website with their mouse on their desktop or laptop. It is a multi-device world out there: tablets, phones, and Surfaces, oh my! How do you create an experience for your users so that their screen size is best utilized? Optimized for touch-based devices? In SharePoint 2013, Device Channels help you present your site in the way best suited to whatever device a visitor is browsing from. As the designer, you get to think about what the experience of your site should be on all different form factors, differentiated by user agent substring assigned to up to 10 different channels. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each channel can target multiple devices. For example, you can have one channel for both Windows Phones and iPhones because they are of similar screen size, and a separate channel for the iPad. You can use a different master page and CSS per channel, and you can also target content to particular channels, all while having the exact same URL (which is great for usability and search engine optimization). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By using the Device Channel infrastructure, you get the opportunity to use Device Channel Panels, which is a great asset for content targeting. Content that you put inside one of these panels is rendered only on the channels you specify based on server-side logic, which decreases the page load time and the number of bytes sent over the wire. Combining these panels with a responsive CSS design makes for a faster and more streamlined user experience. Rather than having different channels based on screen size as in the previous example, you could have an "iOS" substring-based channel that captures iPads, iPhones, and iPad minis and sends a single master page that loads different CSS based on what screen resolution the device is. For example, if you were the Windows Phone team, you could target iOS devices and create a panel to advertise Windows Phone.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://blogs.office.com/resized-image.ashx/__size/550x0/__key/CommunityServer-Blogs-Components-WeblogFiles/00-00-00-00-64/8231.SHAREPOINT-IMAGE-02.png" border="0" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure 2 and Figure 3.&lt;/strong&gt; Side-by-side design mockups of the browser and mobile experiences for a news site based on the Cross-Site Collection Publishing feature, using responsive CSS, Device Channel Panels, and a display template that changes the appearance of Content Search Web Part results based on Device Channels.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post was an introduction to how you can easily define your company's online brand using the tools you're most comfortable with and SharePoint 2013's strong content-management system. To learn more, go check out all the content our documentation writers have written for you on MSDN. The articles &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/jj163242.aspx"&gt;Build sites for SharePoint 2013&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/jj822363.aspx"&gt;Overview of Design Manager in SharePoint 2013&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/jj733518.aspx"&gt;Develop the site design in SharePoint 2013&lt;/a&gt; are some great starting places. Happy designing! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;--Alyssa Levitz, SharePoint Program Manager&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="http://blogs.office.com/aggbug.aspx?PostID=35952" width="1" height="1"&gt;</description><category domain="http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/tags/SharePoint+2013/default.aspx">SharePoint 2013</category><category domain="http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/tags/web+technologies/default.aspx">web technologies</category><category domain="http://blogs.office.com/b/sharepoint/archive/tags/SharePoint/default.aspx">SharePoint</category></item></channel></rss>